Finding Aid for the Waldo Salt Papers, 1936-1987
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
- PRODUCED FILMS
  - MIDNIGHT COWBOY (1969)
    - Script Material
      - Script, l968. Incl. revisions and annotations with dates. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Revised script, various dates, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Script by Jack Gelber. lst draft, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Script by Jack Gelber. 2nd draft, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - MR. WINKLE GOES TO WAR (1944)
    - Script Material
      - Script, "3rd draft- estimating", 12/17/43. In collaboration with George Corey. (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - RACHEL AND THE STRANGER (1948)
    - Script Material
      - Scene-sequence outline, n.d., 10p; script, "1st draft continuity", with shot breakdown, 11/12/46, 148p. (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Script, "revised final", 7/28/47. 133p. 2 copies. (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - SERPICO (1973)
    - Awards
      - Writers Guild of America: Nomination for Best Written American Drama Adapted from Another Medium, l973. (Box 116, Folder -)
      - Writers Guild of America: Best Written American Drama Adapted from Another Medium, l973. (Box 116, Folder -)
      - Mystery Writers of America: Edgar Allan Poe Special Award, [1973]. (Box 116, Folder -)
      - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences: Nomination for Best Screenplay, l973. (Box 117, Folder -)
    - Clippings
      - Film review by Vincent Canby, The New York Times, 12/6/73. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Two letters announcing nominations for "Serpico" screenplay: 3/1/74, by Walter Mirisch- Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences; 3/20/74, by Mystery Writers of America. Letter from FCA Agency concerning unusual policemen in Los Angeles, 8/19/75. (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Legal correspondence with Produzioni De Laurentiis, Jennorah Productions, Inc. and others, concerning W.Salt's agreement to write "Serpico" screenplay and his participation in the profits; legal correspondence regarding payment of profits. 1972-76. (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Publicity Material
      - Press book, 4p; advertising pamphlet, 8p. (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Script Material
      - Two copies of scene breakdown: one handwritten and photocopied (n.d., 30p), and typed version of the same (February 197l, 11p). (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Background notes on structure, characters and scenes, November l972-January l973. Annotated. 62p. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Rough draft, 11/7/72-12-14-72. Incl. revisions, annotations and background notes, chronologically arranged. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - 1st draft, 12/15/72-12/18/72. Annotated. 158p. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - 2nd draft, 1/10/73-2/9/73. 172p. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Script, 3/4/73-3/20/73, with revisions. 140p. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Master File, 11/7/72-12/3/72. Script, incl. revisions, annotations and background notes, chronologically arranged. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Master File, 12/3/72-12/14/72. Script, incl. revisions, annotations and background notes, chronologically arranged. (folder 2 of 2). (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Master File, 12/15/72-1/24/73. Script, incl. revisions, chronologically arranged. (folder 1 of 3). (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Master File, 1/24/73-3/6/73. Script, incl. revisions, chronologically arranged. (folder 2 of 3). (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Master File, 3/6/73-3/20/73. Script, incl. revisions, chronologically arranged. (folder 3 of 3). (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Final script/blue pages; revisions 3/29/73-4/2/73. 3 versions. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, l973. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations, l973. (folder 2 of 2). (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Tape transcripts of scenes and dialogues, 1972. 43p. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - "Serpico" (novel) by Peter Maas. Typed manuscript, 419p. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - THE SHOPWORN ANGEL (1938)
    - Publicity Material
      - Publicity card, with names of cast and screenwriter. (5x6). (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - TARAS BULBA (1962)
    - Notebook
      - Notes and sketches for "Taras Bulba" script, incl. drawings, [1959]. (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Script Material
      - Script, 7/6/61, incl. blue and pink pages with revisions, dated. 142p. Note on cover: "Property of Harold Hecht Productions, Inc.". (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - TONIGHT WE RAID CALAIS (1943)
    - Publicity Material
      - Press-book, 3p. (2 copies). (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - WILD MAN OF BORNEO (1941)
    - Script Material
      - Script, "complete, okayed by Mr. J.Mankiewicz", 10/14/40. 108p. (Box 119, Folder 2)
- PRODUCED TELEVISION PROGRAMS
  - THE ADVENTURES OF ROBIN HOOD (TV series, 1955-58)
      - Script material: outlines for several episodes, using pseudonym Arthur Behrstock, n.d.; scripts: "Isabelle of Angouleme", n.d., 34p; "My Brother's Keeper", n.d., 38p; The Walking Trees of Sherwood", n.d., 37p. Air dates not verified. (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Script material for several episodes, using pseudonym Arthur Behrstock, n.d. Scripts: "A Year and a Day," "The Knight of the Black Patch," "The Robber Baron," "Lincoln Green." (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with producers and story editors (Sapphire Films Ltd.) regarding scripts, rewrites and payments for various episodes, using his name or pseudonyms "M.L.Davenport"/"Arthur Behrstock", 1956-58. (Box 80, Folder 47)
  - THE BUCCANEERS (TV series, 1956-57)
      - Script: "The Surgeon of Sangre Rojo", 34p. Aired CBS, 11-24-56. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "Dan Tempest's War with Spain", 34p. Aired CBS, 10-6-56. Incl: research notes, 4p. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Prize of Andalusia", 33p. Aired CBS, 3-30-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Gunpowder Plot", 33p. Aired CBS, 11-10-56. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "Gentleman Jack and the Lady", 34p. Aired CBS, 12-29-56. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "Dangerous Cargo", 36p. Aired CBS, 1-5-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Printer's Devil", 35p. Aired CBS, 6-8-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Spy Aboard", 37p. Aired CBS, 4-13-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Indian Fighter", 35p. Aired CBS, 4-27-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Script: "The Return of Calico Jack", 34p. Aired CBS, 2-2-57. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with producers and story editors (Sapphire Films Ltd.) regarding scripts and rewrites for various episodes, 1956-58. (Box 80, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence with producers regarding script revisions and research, 1956 (6 items); script material regarding series format, incl. list with episodes and authors (9 items); research material (14 items); typed and hand-written notes (15 items). (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - ESPIONAGE (TV series, 1963-64)
      - Script material for episode "Never Turn your Back on a Friend", aired NBC 1/1/64. Incl: story idea, outline and notes, n.d.; 3 versions of script (one dated 10/9/63), signed M.L.Davenport (W.Salt's pseudonym). (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - FOR THE PEOPLE (TV series, 1965)
      - Script material: scene breakdown for episode "Go Fight City Hall"; script for episode #13 (aired CBS, 5/9/65), dated 3/23/65, for Plautus Productions, Inc., 2 copies; outline of series, by E.Kinoy; shooting schedule and call sheet, March 1965. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - IVANHOE (TV series, 1957-59)
      - Script material: series outline by B.Berenberg, 5/7/56, for Screen Gems, Inc, 49p; annotated scripts for episodes: #12 (n.d., 34p); #15 by R.Soderberg (7/26/57, 34p), no author (n.d., 40p). Air dates not verified. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Annotated scripts for episodes: #16 (n.d., 3 versions); #20 (n.d., 35p); #21 (n.d., 35p); #29 by Felix Van Lieu -pseudonym for W.Salt- (ll/26/57, 39p); hand-written notes and sketches. Air dates not verified. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Copies of musical score and lyrics for programs # 15 (1 song), #18 (3 songs), #20 (2 songs) and #21 (1 song). Words by M.L.Davenport (pseudonym) and music by Benedict Berenberg. (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - THE NURSES (TV series, 1962-64)
      - Script materials: two versions of treatment for episode "Last Rites for a Rag Doll", one dated 5/26/64; three versions of script, dated 8/5/64, 10/21/64 and 10/25/64. (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials, 1964, with annotations and corrections. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Uncollated script materials, 1964, with annotations and corrections. (folder 2 of 2). (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Script materials: series outline, with notes on characters and plots, 4/6/62, 20p; script, "2nd revised": "Edward Victor DeMarino", by Alvin Sargent, 10/30/63. (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - THE SWISS FAMILY ROBINSON (1958)
      - Script for television special. Adapted from J.R.Wyss' novel by M.L.Davenport (pseudonym for W.Salt). Note on cover: "revised, 9/22/58". Aired NBC, 10/12/58. (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - THE SWORD OF FREEDOM (TV series, 1957-58)
      - Scripts and outlines for Sapphire Films, Ltd, Great Britain: #6, "Portrait in Emerald Green", 7/4/57, 29p; #16, "Serenade in Red", 11/20/57, 28p; #20, "Forgery in Red Chalk", 10/24/57, 28p; #24, "Chart of Gold", 11/25/57, 26p. Air dates not verified. (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with producers and story editors (Sapphire Films Ltd.) regarding scripts, rewrites and payments for various episodes, using his name or pseudonyms "M.L.Davenport"/"Arthur Behrstock", 1956-58. (Box 80, Folder 47)
- UNPRODUCED FILMS
  - THE ARTFUL DODGER
    - Notebook
      - Notes, sketches and drawings for "The Artful Dodger", n.d. (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Research Material
      - Research notes, incl. newspaper clipping on military draft and hippies, hand-written in notebook under heading "Research Notes", n.d. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Script Material
      - Two versions of story outline: one, n.d., 5p; the other, 1/4/67, 8p. (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Background notes on characters and plot, hand-written in notebook under headings "Script Notes" and "Book Notes", n.d. (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Notes on 1st draft of script, 9/18/67, 5p; rewrite notes, 4/3/68, 9p. (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - Master File, January 1967-April 1969. Script, incl. story outline, rewrite and continuity notes, with dates, annotations and corrections (folder 1 of 2). (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - Master File, January 1967-April 1969. Script, incl. story outline, rewrite and continuity notes, with dates, annotations and corrections (folder 2 of 2). (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Script, June-September 1967. 192p. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Script, June-September 1967. 192p. (Another version of 59-6, with annotations and corrections). (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Script, October 1968-April 1969. 115p. (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations, corrections and dates, l968. (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations, corrections and dates, l967-69. Incl: hand-written notes on legal size sheets. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - BEAU BRUMMEL
    - Script Material
      - Various versions of script: "temporary incomplete", 3/15/40, 119p (2 copies, one incomplete); "temporary complete", 6/8/40, 91p; "temporary incomplete", 12/5/40, 23p; version dated 8/20/41, 23p. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - A CONNECTICUT YANKEE IN KING ARTHUR'S COURT
    - Clippings
      - Book review of "The Real Camelot. Paganism and the Arthurian Romances" by John Darrah, in The New York Times, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence with director John Landis regarding the project, 198l-82. Incl: "Rolling Stone" story on accident during "Twilight Zone" shooting, 6/2l/84. 15 items. (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with Universal Pictures, John Landis, Creative Artists Agency, Inc., Jennorah Productions, Inc. (W.Salt) regarding contract to write script, October l981-October 1983. 15 items. (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Invoice sent to W.Salt by University of California Press regarding payment of various Mark Twain works, 1/19/82. (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Script Material
      - Outline of novel by Mark Twain, n.d. 34p. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Master File, March-October 1982. Script, incl. outline of Mark Twain's novel (34p); continuity notes; notes on characters, plot and scenes; revised continuity notes (folder 1 of 2). (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Master File, March-October 1982. Script, incl. outline of Mark Twain's novel (34p); continuity notes; notes on characters, plot and scenes; revised continuity notes (folder 2 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Master file copy, October-November 1982. Script, with a few corrections (folder 1 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Master File, October-November 1982. Script, with a few corrections (folder 2 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Script, 11/27/82. 162p. 2 copies (original and photocopy). (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, 1982-83. Incl: script pages (a few dated 1981); continuity notes; outlines; and Mark Twain quotes (folder 1 of 2). (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, 1982-83. Incl: script pages (a few dated 1981); continuity notes; outlines; and Mark Twain quotes (folder 2 of 2). (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Script materials, with annotations and corrections, 1982-84, not arranged chronologically. Incl: script and continuity notes. (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Script materials, with annotations and corrections, 1983-84, not arranged chronologically. Incl: script and continuity notes. (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - 100 numbered index cards with scene breakdown in relationship to novel; 36 unnumbered index cards with notes on characters, scenes and settings. (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - "A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court" (novel) by Mark Twain, New York, 1963. 334p. Annotated by W.Salt. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - THE DAY THEY GAVE BABIES AWAY
    - Script Material
      - Script, "First draft revised", 9/22/50. 122p. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - DON QUIXOTE
    - Correspondence
      - Four manuscript letters to W.Salt regarding Don Quixote project, one dated 12/10/71, presumably by A.R. Lubin; clippings from trade publications. 8 items. (Box 80, Folder 14)
      - Legal correspondence regarding Memorandum of Agreement between Jennorah Productions (W.Salt) and A.Ronald Lubin, January 1981-November 1983. 4 items. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Research Material
      - "Don Quixote" by Miguel de Cervantes. English version of novel: "The Portable Don Quixote", ed. Samuel Putnam, n.d., +854p. Disassembled and rearranged by W.Salt, with annotations and 52 marks on pages. (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - "Cliff Notes on Don Quixote", l964, 89p. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Script Material
      - Master File, June-August l965. Script, incl. background notes on characters, rewrite notes, and annotations, with dates. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Master File, September-December l965. Script, incl. background notes on characters, scene breakdown, continuity notes, annotations and corrections, with dates (folder 1 of 2). (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Master File, September-December l965. Script, incl. background notes on characters, scene breakdown, continuity notes, annotations and corrections, with dates (folder 2 of 2). (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Master File, January-May l966. Script, incl. background notes on characters and sequences, continuity notes, and annotations, with dates (folder 1 of 2). (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Master File, January-May l966. Script, incl. background notes on characters and sequences, continuity notes, and annotations, with dates (folder 2 of 2). (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Master File, June-October l966. Script, incl. background notes on characters and sequences, notes on rewrites, continuity notes, annotations and corrections, with dates (folder 1 of 2). (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Master File, June-October l966. Script, incl. background notes on characters and sequences, notes on rewrites, continuity notes, annotations and corrections, with dates (folder 2 of 2). (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Master File, November l966-January l967. Script, incl. background notes on characters and sequences, annotations and corrections, with dates. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Script, 1/22/66. 139p. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Script, 2/7/66. Incl. cover with reproduction of drawing by Pablo Picasso. 136p. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Script, 7/27/66. Incl. cover with reproduction of drawing by Pablo Picasso, and annotations. 179p. (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Script, 1/22/67. 129p. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Script, 1/22/67. 129p. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Script, 1/25/67. 126p. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Script, 1/25/67. Same as 29-5 but without dates on each page. The cover page is a photocopy of the reproduction of Picasso's drawing; annotations in pencil. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Script, 3/19/71. Incl. reproduction of Picasso's drawing, and annotations in pencil. 97p. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Script, n.d. 137p. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script materials, dated March 8-10, l97l. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - "Don Quixote" (script) by Laslo Vadnay, l956. Note on cover: "Property of and returnable to Desilu Script Library". 116p. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Hand-written pages with notes on characters, plot and themes, incl. suggestions for rewrites, undated. 13p. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - DOWNHILL
    - Script Material
      - Script, with revisions and annotations, n.d. 116p. (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, November 1968 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Uncollated script materials with annotations and corrections, November 1968 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Uncollated script materials, with annotations and corrections, November 1968 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Script materials with annotations and corrections, incl. scene breakdown; notes on characters, plot and dialogue; etc. n.d. (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - ETHAN FROME
      - Script, "temporary- Warner Bros. Studios", 1/28/42, 111p. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - FLUX II
      - Script, October 1968-April 1969. 115p. (See Box 59, Folder 3/4/5 and Box 60, Folder 1). (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - A HANDSOME MAN
    - Correspondence
      - Legal correspondence regarding agreement to write and produce "A Handsome Man", September 198l-July 1982. 10 items. (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Two letters by producer Jerome Hellman concerned about W.Salt's delay in finishing the script, 11/3/8l and 12/9/81. (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Research Material
      - Research on Ireland. Incl: memos to Jerome Hellman and W.Salt by G.Mutrux regarding locations, bibliography and filmography on Ireland, July 1981; photocopies of travel books; photos of Irish landscape. (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Photocopies of articles and chapters from various books regarding Irish history, politics, culture and geography. Incl. brochures, maps and a few photos. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Script Material
      - Tape transcript (10 tapes) of story conference notes taken during meetings with producer Jerome Hellman, August 1981. 454p. (folder 1 of 3). (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Tape transcript (10 tapes) of story conference notes taken during meetings with producer Jerome Hellman, August 1981. 454p. (folder 2 of 3). (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Tape transcript (10 tapes) of story conference notes taken during meetings with producer Jerome Hellman, August 1981. 454p. (folder 3 of 3). (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Treatment, January-February 1982. 102p. 2 copies: one, annotated. (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Master File, August 1981-February 1982. Script, incl. outline of novel (15p); continuity notes; notes on characters and plot; with annotations (folder 1 of 2). (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Master File, August 1981-February 1982. Script, incl. outline of novel (15p); continuity notes; notes on characters and plot; with annotations (folder 2 of 2). (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Photocopy of typed script of novel "The Flight of the Earls", previous title of "A Handsome Man". Incl: photocopies of letter and memo to Jerome Hellman and P.Matson, regarding progress and changes in novel and impact on screenplay (folder 1 of 2). (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Photocopy of typed script of novel "The Flight of the Earls", previous title of "A Handsome Man". Incl: photocopies of letter and memo to Jerome Hellman and P.Matson, regarding progress and changes in novel and impact on screenplay (folder 2 of 2). (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - HEMINGWAY
    - Clippings
      - Clippings from newspapers and magazines concerning the project and Hemingway's life. (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence regarding the project, incl. letters to W.Salt from Sydney Pollack, 8/17/79; Jay Weston cancelling project, 4/13/81; various notes from Mary Welsh Hemingway. 21 items. (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Legal correspondence regarding Agreement between Jennorah Productions, Inc. (W.Salt) and MGM on screenplay and film. April 1977-June 1979. 8 items. (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence with MGM concerning W.Salt's research, sets and locations for film, etc., May-October 1977; invoices and plane ticket for W.Salt charged to MGM, 1979. 6 items. (Box 80, Folder 27)
      - Manuscript letter signed "Betsy" [Douglas], 8/28/77; typed letter signed "Clara", commenting on script, 5/14/79. (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - Legal correspondence between MGM and Jennorah Productions concerning script entitled "How it Was", based on Mary Welsh Hemingway's work, l977-79. 5 items. (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Photos
      - Group shot with W.Salt, Fidel Castro, Mary Welsh Hemingway, in La Habana (Cuba) during research trip for "Hemingway" project, [197?]. b/w and color, 8x10; inscribed on the back. 3 photos. (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - Photo of W.Salt and Mary Welsh Hemingway during research for "Hemingway" project, [197?]. b/w, 8x10; inscribed on the back. (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Research Material
      - Chronology of E.Hemingway's life: 1899-1943. Incl. typed biografical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research. (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Chronology of E.Hemingway's life: 1944-1961. Incl. typed biografical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research. (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Chronology of E.Hemingway's life: 1899-1953. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research (A different version of box 40, folders 4/5). (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Chronology of E.Hemingway's life: 1954-1961. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research (A different version of box 40, folders 4/5). (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Chronology of E.Hemingway's life: 1899-1961. Incl. typed biografical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research (Not the same as box 40, folders 4/5). (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Photocopy of chronology of E.Hemingway's life, incl. typed biografical data from various sources, cited and arranged year by year, with dates of research (A different version of box 41, folder 3). (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Index to research on E.Hemingway done by W.Salt: it lists contents of the XVI folders with biographical research, folders with bibliographical research and research on Mary Welsh Hemingway. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Research on E.Hemingway. "I": 1918-33. Incl. typed biographical data from various sources; photocopies of articles in books, magazines, journals and newspapers; with dates of research and index. 28 items. (Box 42, Folder 1)